[SPEAKER_01]: This is my notebook I take with me of all the players.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where did you get your information from me?
[SPEAKER_01]: About me?
[SPEAKER_01]: In the encyclopedias.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_01]: And I couldn't find you in Who's Who in Baseball.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess you didn't play enough games any one year.
[SPEAKER_01]: You couldn't do what?
[SPEAKER_01]: In Who's Who in Baseball, that little rugby book came out every year.
[SPEAKER_01]: I couldn't find it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That was usually a pretty good source.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they didn't have too many people in that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So I went through the baseball encyclopedia here and got your record.
[SPEAKER_01]: So why don't you just tell me about your family and where you grew up, first of all.
[SPEAKER_01]: You mean from the time I was born?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's so good.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were born in Anderson, Indiana, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was born right out of Anderson on a farm.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_00]: In Madison County.
[SPEAKER_00]: I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: You got this thing on now?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, is that okay?
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, I think that's what I want to get now.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I played semi-pro ball around Muncie when I was a boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, now, who'd you play with?
[SPEAKER_00]: Semi-pro ball, factory league.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was 12 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went into a glass house to work.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, what one?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was Hemingway's.
[SPEAKER_01]: She's a glass historian.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was Hemingway's then.
[SPEAKER_00]: It later became Owens-Illinois, but it was Hemingway's Glass House, and we made insulators, prune jars.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I was a glass worker for trade.
[SPEAKER_00]: I started playing semifinal ball around here, and Cincinnati tried to sign me.
[SPEAKER_00]: They wanted to send me to...
[SPEAKER_00]: Senegal, Virginia or someplace like that.
[SPEAKER_01]: When would that have been?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember the year?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, that was way around, back around 1920.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I wouldn't go with him because I was making pretty good money in the glass house.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I was getting $50 a game for catching at Connersville, Indiana.
[SPEAKER_00]: What league was this?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it was just the same pro league.
[SPEAKER_00]: And of course,
[SPEAKER_00]: The Meyerleys didn't pay no money then.
[SPEAKER_00]: $125, $150 a month was top salary.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I wouldn't go.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had an opportunity to?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who with?
[SPEAKER_00]: I had an opportunity.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cincinnati wanted to send me to...
[SPEAKER_00]: This place in Virginia?
[SPEAKER_00]: This place in Stoney Key, Virginia was the name of the town.
[SPEAKER_00]: And my wife talked me into going into professional ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was a young fella out of Newcastle, Indiana, who was managing Jackson and the old Central League up in Michigan.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was he?
[SPEAKER_02]: His name was...
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't even think of his name now, it's been so long ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Danny Jenkins.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jenkins.
[SPEAKER_00]: Danny Jenkins.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the manager of the Jacksonville team.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I went up there and they went, well they just couldn't support them and they busted up about the middle of the lake and they sent the franchise over to Ionia, Michigan.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ionia, Michigan where the pen is.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I stayed with them that year, and Muskegon bought me the following year.
[SPEAKER_00]: This would be 1920?
[SPEAKER_00]: That was 1920.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were with Jackson and Owen.
[SPEAKER_00]: Jackson and Owen, and then 1921, Muskegon, Michigan got my contract from them.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd you do in that year, 1920?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember your batting average?
[SPEAKER_00]: I really don't even know what I did do.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, back in them days, I didn't even know there was a big lake.
[SPEAKER_00]: All I knew was just play ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: I loved to play ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: You say your wife talked you into going into ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about this.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you want to play or you weren't interested that much yourself?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I was interested, but I was a young married fellow and I had one boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I couldn't see myself leaving for that kind of money.
[SPEAKER_00]: But everybody told me that I was good enough, that I could go on.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I decided to take her word and I went.
[SPEAKER_00]: When were you married?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was married in 1970.
[SPEAKER_00]: And was Mrs. Kraus from Muncie or Anderson?
[SPEAKER_01]: She was from Muncie.
[SPEAKER_01]: And how did you meet her?
[SPEAKER_00]: Lived right across the street from her when I was a kid.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, a schoolgirl.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, lived right across the street from her.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I grew up to Muskegon, Michigan and
[SPEAKER_00]: I had an outstanding year and the White Sox bought me and took me up in the middle of the year in July, 23.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were with Muskegon in 23 then, part of the season.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I was with Muskegon part of the season, 23.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sold me the white socks.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the manager of Muskegon?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the manager of Muskegon was Danny... Was it the Jenkins family name?
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't Danny Jenkins, it was another Danny.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll swear I don't remember his name either, but I do know that he got burned up working on his automobile.
[SPEAKER_00]: He got under the car and
[SPEAKER_00]: I just can't remember that fellow's name, save my life.
[SPEAKER_02]: But anyway, I never will forget the day they saw me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I didn't even know there was a big lake, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they told me they saw me to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, well, I'm not going to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I don't even have clothes fit to wear over to Chicago, a big city like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I'm going to stay here.
[SPEAKER_00]: They told me to get on a boat.
[SPEAKER_00]: They bought me a new suit and dressed me all up.
[SPEAKER_01]: These are the owner?
[SPEAKER_00]: The owner of the Muskegon Club.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did they pay for you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Five thousand dollars.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did Chicago hear of you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did they have a scout out?
[SPEAKER_00]: They had a scout out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you know this?
[SPEAKER_01]: Big Ed Walsh, football pitcher.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, that's right, Ed Walsh.
[SPEAKER_01]: He must have heard about you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he just scouting around and happened to see you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, evidently, I don't know how he...
[SPEAKER_00]: But anyway, they picked me, and then later they took Bud Clancy from the same club.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, that year?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, no, the following year, I think it was.
[SPEAKER_00]: First baseman.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a pretty good team you had.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd the team finish?
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, you left in mid-year, but...
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know how they did finish.
[SPEAKER_00]: I really don't know how they did finish.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I played in Chicago until 19...
[SPEAKER_00]: The winter of 1930, they sold me to Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_00]: Traded me to Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_01]: I want to hear more about your early life now.
[SPEAKER_01]: About life on the farm.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I didn't spend any life on a farm.
[SPEAKER_00]: My folks moved to Mussie when I was about four years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I see.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did your father do?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a contractor.
[SPEAKER_00]: Carpenter.
[SPEAKER_01]: He had been working the farm, though, prior to them?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he never did farm.
[SPEAKER_00]: He worked for farmers, but he'd done carpenter work and cement work.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just went around the country.
[SPEAKER_00]: We moved to Muncie when I was a kid.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, no, I was about four years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: You had brothers and sisters?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, my, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Fourteen of us kids.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nine boys and five girls.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had a baseball team in your family.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we had one, but I was the only one who played.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were they older or younger?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I had one brother older, and the rest of them were all younger than me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he play ball at all?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you happen to start playing ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Just out in the sand?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just a bunch of kids out in the field.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's where I played.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to
[SPEAKER_00]: Eat breakfast, my mother would never see me after dark.
[SPEAKER_00]: You really liked to play?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I loved to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: You gotta love to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you stand out above the other kids, I mean, in town?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, yeah, way out.
[SPEAKER_00]: When I was only 12, 13 years old, I caught for the men.
[SPEAKER_00]: Men team here in town.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Were you pretty big for your age?
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you full-grown then, or were you... No, I was a good-sized boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, you're about like I am now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about school?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you play in school?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, we didn't have any teams in school.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I only went to the sixth grade in school.
[SPEAKER_00]: See, there were so many of us kids that I went to work to help my dad feed the rest of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I went into a glass house when I was only 12 years old.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't have any law that made you go to school?
[SPEAKER_00]: If they did, I don't know anything about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did you have to pick the glass out?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's the only place I could get a job.
[SPEAKER_00]: They couldn't keep boys in there, it was so hot.
[SPEAKER_00]: They couldn't keep boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: I started in as a carry-in boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then later took out what we called taking out and screwing out insulators.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then when the shop would close down, we were night turned.
[SPEAKER_00]: When the shop would close down about three o'clock in the morning, everybody going home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Some of us kids get up on a ring hole, and that's how I learned to gather glass.
[SPEAKER_00]: So about a year later, I was a gathering boy in Prussia.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I started making pretty good money.
[SPEAKER_00]: One reason I didn't want to go play professional ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's pretty hard work though, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: It was hot.
[SPEAKER_01]: It wasn't hard.
[SPEAKER_01]: It was hot.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wouldn't you want to get out in the open air and play ball?
[SPEAKER_01]: Wouldn't you want to get out?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it was quite a lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have much time to play ball when you worked in the last plant?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: We played well.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, we played every Saturday and Sunday.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: This was a city league in Muncie?
[SPEAKER_01]: It was a city league.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was an organized league you were playing?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, just city league.
[SPEAKER_00]: Factory boys would get together and form teams.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd play among ourselves.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, of course, after I got to playing pretty good, they started wanting me in these little towns around here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Reputation.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You were a catcher at this time?
[SPEAKER_01]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_01]: What position would you be playing?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was a catcher all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I could never try to play anything else.
[SPEAKER_00]: But something happened real funny.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's a little town by the name of Eaton over here north of Muncie.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I used to ride a bicycle from Muncie to Eaton.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's 12 miles.
[SPEAKER_00]: Play a game, they give me a quarter.
[SPEAKER_00]: So another little town farther north of Eaton by the name of Montpelier.
[SPEAKER_00]: They came over there and played us one day and this manager, I don't know what his name was either.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, why don't you come over to Montpierre and play with us?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I'll give you more money than they're giving you.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, how much will you give me?
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I'll give you 75 cents and pay your way on the interurban there and back.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I'll be over there next Sunday.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then, after that, then I started going to Connersville, and we started making good money.
[SPEAKER_00]: We kept $50 to $75 a game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's when the scouts from Cincinnati saw me and wanted me to go away.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any particular scout contact you, or you remember talking to him?
[SPEAKER_01]: I don't remember his name, but... What kind of ballparks would you play in at Montpelier and Connersville?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just rough
[SPEAKER_00]: Just a ballpark, just all skin diamonds, no grass.
[SPEAKER_01]: Any grandstands at all, or fences?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just a little grandstand.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we had a fence here in Muncie.
[SPEAKER_01]: Didn't you have any artificial turf?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh no, my land, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had mud.
[SPEAKER_01]: Real mud, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: I oftentimes wonder what the old fellas must think when they see that artificial turf.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh no, we played on, I mean it was rough.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know how infielders come up with the balls half the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: They really took bad odds.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the starting of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you actually got started in professional ball at a later age, didn't you?
[SPEAKER_00]: I was 25 years old when the White Sox bought me.
[SPEAKER_00]: 25.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's kind of late.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was the only catcher at that time that ever went out of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: class B league and stayed in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never was farmed back out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I stayed right up there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were there any other fellows who made it big who were in the central league when you were with Muskegon, do you remember?
[SPEAKER_01]: Any of the teams?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Bud Clancy was one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he's the only one I know of in that old Central Lake.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now tell me, what was your feeling when you got to Chicago?
[SPEAKER_01]: You're a big time... Well, I'll tell you.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was dumbfounded, to tell you the truth.
[SPEAKER_00]: Have you been to a big city before?
[SPEAKER_00]: Never been, never been to a big city before in my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got off of the boat in Chicago about six o'clock in the morning.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I hadn't had breakfast yet.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't know where to go or what to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got a cab and told them to take me out to the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_00]: I sat out at the ballpark until they opened the gates.
[SPEAKER_01]: I went in and told them who I was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who did you first report to?
[SPEAKER_00]: Kid Gleason was the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did he say?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the first thing, I had one of them great big green gloves that catchers use.
[SPEAKER_00]: That is, we used, same pro players used.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just like a pillow, ball head just go poof, no noise or no nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Had cheap ball shoes on.
[SPEAKER_00]: When you get them wet, they'd stretch about that big.
[SPEAKER_01]: They brought a uniform with you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, they didn't take my uniform.
[SPEAKER_00]: I took my shoes and gloves.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I never will forget that, because the first day out, Kid Gleason, the manager of White's house, he said, let me see that glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: after we'd taken our workout, had me out there throwing around the bases, he said, let me see that glove, and I handed him my glove, and he took it and threw it up in the grandstand.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, you're in the big leagues now, you gotta have some tools.
[SPEAKER_00]: That liked to scare me to death.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when I get up in the clubhouse, I had two brand new short-model catching gloves,
[SPEAKER_00]: And a guy from Spalding fitted me with a pair of featherweight shoes, which I didn't know what a featherweight shoe was in my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: What kind of gloves are those?
[SPEAKER_00]: Shock?
[SPEAKER_00]: Ray Shock.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, Ray Shock.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bicep catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a glove model there.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I used that glove all the way through my career.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, that model glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, uh, they took pretty good care of me, but he scared me to death.
[SPEAKER_01]: What are these feather shoes?
[SPEAKER_00]: Real just like kid gloves on your feet.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was this a special advantage to a catcher?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody used them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Make you run faster?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I could run like a deer.
[SPEAKER_00]: I put them things on, I just felt like I was flying.
[SPEAKER_01]: They hadn't gotten down in the minor leagues with those yet, had they?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: My land, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: A minor league player couldn't afford to buy it.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were putting their $22 in them days.
[SPEAKER_01]: You mean you had to buy your shoes in Muskegon?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had to buy everything.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not the uniform.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, we didn't buy the uniform.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the other equipment.
[SPEAKER_00]: Shoes and gloves.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gloves and shoes and sweatshirts and stuff like that we had to buy.
[SPEAKER_00]: How'd you travel in the Central League?
[SPEAKER_00]: In the old Central League on a bus.
[SPEAKER_00]: And inter-urban.
[SPEAKER_01]: We traveled in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you make any overnight stops or did you come back home?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, we made overnight stops.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we'd stay.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where would you stay overnight?
[SPEAKER_00]: Sometimes we'd stay two or three days.
[SPEAKER_00]: We rode in urban when we could.
[SPEAKER_00]: I like we'd go from bus gigging
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we'd go from Muskegon to Hamlin, Ontario.
[SPEAKER_00]: We'd ride a train.
[SPEAKER_00]: If we'd go from Muskegon to Grand Rapids, Michigan, we'd ride in urban.
[SPEAKER_00]: If we'd go to some of them other towns a little closer by, we'd ride a bus.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just according to, I suppose, the cheapest way to go.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: What kind of clubhouse facilities did you have in Central Lake?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, nothing to brag about.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was just an old wooden locker.
[SPEAKER_00]: And just an old shower where you walk in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nothing like the big leagues where they got nice showers, nice locker room.
[SPEAKER_00]: How much expense money did you get in Muskegon?
[SPEAKER_00]: We didn't get any expense money.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd make us eat
[SPEAKER_00]: hamburger joint.
[SPEAKER_00]: They'd take us.
[SPEAKER_01]: We didn't get no expense money.
[SPEAKER_01]: They'd take the whole team together, eat in one place, and then they'd pay the bill themselves.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let me check and see how we're coming through here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, now back to the White Sox.
[SPEAKER_01]: How was Kit Gleason to you?
[SPEAKER_00]: Kit Gleason was a real, real fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: I played, let's see, I played under
[SPEAKER_00]: Kid Gleason only stayed there that one year, 23.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they give the job to Frank Chance.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he died while we was in spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: In 24.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pneumonia.
[SPEAKER_00]: In the spring of 24?
[SPEAKER_00]: In the spring of 24.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they made Johnny Evers, who was their coach, they made him the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I played under Evers in 24 and
[SPEAKER_00]: Twenty-five.
[SPEAKER_00]: Twenty-five, they give it to... Eddie Collins, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Eddie Collins.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then I think Eddie Collins had it one, maybe two years.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they give it to Lena Blackburn.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then Lena, they let Lena go after a year.
[SPEAKER_00]: I believe it was a year, and then they give it to Ray Shock.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ray Shock managed them for two years.
[SPEAKER_01]: Wasn't this demoralizing, having so many changes in the managers?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, it wasn't good.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, you didn't know whether he was going or coming.
[SPEAKER_00]: And from Ray Shock, then they give it to Oney Bush.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, only Bush.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the last one.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who was the best of all those?
[SPEAKER_01]: Or couldn't you pick one up?
[SPEAKER_01]: Any standout of knowing the baseball best or being the best manager?
[SPEAKER_00]: Eddie Collins.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I didn't play for Gleason long enough to really know about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Eddie Collins was the best.
[SPEAKER_00]: How about Evers?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was a radical guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: A what?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a radical sort of a fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: In what way?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he's one of these guys who hide behind a tree to see if he's coming in at midnight.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was rough.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a rough guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who was the most lenient of them all?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'd say Ray Sharp was.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you think a manager can be pretty lenient and still be a real good manager?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: But he's got to have the respect of his players.
[SPEAKER_00]: How does he get that?
[SPEAKER_00]: By being lenient?
[SPEAKER_00]: By just being, just being one of the boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was Sharp that way?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Ray Sharp was about, so was Eddie Collins.
[SPEAKER_01]: And Sharp, he was still on the team when you joined them?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Who else did they have catching?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, let's see.
[SPEAKER_01]: How'd they happen to need you, in other words, in 1923?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, in 24, I did all the catching.
[SPEAKER_00]: Shulk sat on the bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had Harry McCurdy, and we had...
[SPEAKER_00]: My little, what the hell was his name?
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't remember this other catcher's name, but anyway, something happened.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we got Moe Berg over there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Moe Berg, he was a shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come to us as a shortstop.
[SPEAKER_00]: And all of us catchers broke our fingers this one particular day, and they had no catchers.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they put Moe Berg in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said he used to catch in high school, and that's how he started to become a catcher, and he turned out to be a good catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: What year was this then?
[SPEAKER_00]: 23?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, let's see, that must have been around 20...
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know, it was the year Collins had the club, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: 26 or 27.
[SPEAKER_01]: You all got a broken finger or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah I got a broken finger.
[SPEAKER_00]: Shelton got a broken finger and Aaron McCurdy got a broken finger.
[SPEAKER_01]: I was very shocked as a player when you came up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he pretty much over the top?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah he was, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell me about these fellas who were with the team during the 1919 World Series.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did they ever talk much about it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Never said a word.
[SPEAKER_00]: Never heard
[SPEAKER_00]: The only guy I ever heard talk was little Dickie Kerr, left-hand pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he still with them?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he came back and tried to pitch while I was there.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he just couldn't, he didn't have anything.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did he say very much?
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't say too much, only just said it's pretty rough to win when they're half the team trying to dump you.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's about all he said.
[SPEAKER_00]: Collins never did say anything, shock.
[SPEAKER_00]: Schalk never did say anything to any of us about it.
[SPEAKER_01]: I guess that's the kind of thing you just don't talk about.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, that's right.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there any of the players on the club that weren't there at that time talk much about it?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was this a hanging over routine at this time?
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why, you see when I went up there, Judge Landers broke that club all up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that was one reason they started, well I suppose that's how they picked me.
[SPEAKER_00]: They brought, well they brought a lot of fellas in about that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: See they, they barred all those guys.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you ever meet any of them?
[SPEAKER_00]: Never met any of them, uh uh.
[SPEAKER_00]: No I never did meet any of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They never did, any of them ever come around I know of.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever meet Comiskey?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Tell a little bit about him if you would.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was a real, he was a real fellow.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you something funny about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Harry Grabner was the general manager when I was up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I was just a kid and when I went up from Muskegon, Michigan, I was only making $150 a month at Muskegon.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, when I went to Chicago,
[SPEAKER_00]: This grabber called me in the office to sign a contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I had to, I didn't have any idea what a big league ballplayer made.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they played a city series up there with the Cubs every fall.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Harry says, now he said, I'm gonna give you $375 a month.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he told me that I'd get a share of the city series they played every fall.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, $375 a month sounded like a lot of money to me, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I signed a contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that year we beat the Cubs.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I caught three of the games in that series.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I come back, I got about $1,200 bonus out of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I come back home and I took that check and started building this house.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's how I got this house, took that first money.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was in 23, the very first year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that winter I sat here and kept waiting for a letter to come, contract to come for me to sign.
[SPEAKER_00]: None come.
[SPEAKER_00]: So pretty soon I got a letter from me to meet the club in Indianapolis, catch a train that they was on.
[SPEAKER_00]: to go to Florida to spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: I still didn't know about any contract, but I went.
[SPEAKER_00]: So when I get down in Florida, I get to talking to Chuck, and Chuck and I had become real good friends.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, he showed me everything about catchment there was to know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Collins was a real good friend of mine.
[SPEAKER_00]: He told me
[SPEAKER_00]: And I asked him, I said, how come I didn't get no contract?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't have no contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: They said, yeah, you've got a contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, I never signed any.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Colin spoke up and said, did you sign a contract last year?
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I'll bet you you signed it for two years and didn't know it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I sure did if I didn't know it because I didn't get no contract.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I got off to a flying start.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, they couldn't get me out.
[SPEAKER_00]: I hit about almost 400 against the Giants all the way back.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the more I thought about that guy doing me that way, the madder I got.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Collins says, now when you get back to Chicago, he said, you go into the office and talk to Mr. Comiskey.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: So when I get back to the office, I saw his colored chauffeur there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, is Mr. Comiskey... No, before I did that, I went up to the office.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I had to go through Grabner's office to get to his office.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I knocked on the door, and I asked for Mr. Comiskey, and Grabner says he ain't here.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says he's up in the woods, up in Wisconsin.
[SPEAKER_01]: Camp Jerome.
[SPEAKER_00]: So I just turned around and walked back, and when I did, I saw his collared chauffeur there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I walked up to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, Ernie, I said,
[SPEAKER_00]: Is Mr. Comiskey still up in the woods?"
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, no, he's up there in his office.
[SPEAKER_00]: And boy, that burnt me up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, Grabham just told me what?
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, well, he is.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, I'll tell you how to get up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's going the back way.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I didn't know how to get up there the back way.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he showed me how to get up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I went up there and knocked on the door.
[SPEAKER_00]: And real old voice says, come in.
[SPEAKER_00]: I liked to tingle that old man to death when I went in there and started sitting down and talking to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, what can I do for you, young man?
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, well, Mr. Comiskey, I says, uh... Did he know you were on the team?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I...
[SPEAKER_00]: I says, I never signed no contract this year.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, I can't live on the money I'm making.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I'm only $375 a month.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, I've got a family back in Indiana.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I says, I'm buying a home.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I says, I just can't make it on that.
[SPEAKER_00]: And boy, he pushed a button like that and that quick and grabbed her and come in there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you ought to see him, his face when he saw me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, Harry,
[SPEAKER_00]: Bring that young man's contract in there."
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Harry went out and brought that contract in there, and the old man just tore it in two.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, how much you want?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the minute he said that, he had me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I haven't got the least idea, Mr. Kaminsky.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I haven't got the least idea.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, all I know is I've got to have more money.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can't live on this.
[SPEAKER_00]: He studied about two minutes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, well, would $5,000 be all right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Christ, I'd like to fell off of the chair.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, that was big money back them days, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: The big stars only made 9, 10.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'd like to fell over and buy it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, yeah, that'll be fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that was really funny.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know, Comiskey has a reputation of just not paying his players anything.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was one of the reasons for the scandal.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: Lou, that's his boy, he used to go to spring training with us all the time.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Kenny Lyons, he was the best pusher I ever caught.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, he was smart.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Bill Tam, they'd come up from the coast.
[SPEAKER_01]: San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_00]: San Francisco.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they wanted a raise.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Lou said, well, he said, I'll tell you what you do.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, you guys refuse to sign, you'll get it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He says, you'll get it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just refuse to sign.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just don't sign.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ted won $10,000.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd win mile and, I don't know, something like 20, 21 games.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd average 17 every year, I think, something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he talked them into holding out.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's Louis did, the son.
[SPEAKER_00]: The son.
[SPEAKER_00]: So they held out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they, Kim, Bill Cam got it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know whether Ted Lyons ever got it or not, I never did say.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he didn't hold out like Cam did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because Ted was a big, young, single fellow right out of college.
[SPEAKER_00]: Him and I joined the club the same day.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, we've had a lot of experiences on that club.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they used to say, they used to have a club, one a-going and one a-coming.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, back them days.
[SPEAKER_00]: What'd that mean?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they'd release one and bring another one in its place.
[SPEAKER_00]: Just kept them going and coming.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did the contract question, was that handled by Grabner all the time, or was it Kaminsky?
[SPEAKER_00]: Grabner handled it all.
[SPEAKER_01]: He wasn't too honorable.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a Jewish lawyer.
[SPEAKER_00]: They say he was one of the best lawyers around Chicago at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he practicing law at the same time?
[SPEAKER_00]: I imagine he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Moonlighting?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, I don't know why he would sign me unless he said, well, here's a dumb kid from Indiana, just take advantage of him.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's what he did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because I didn't have any idea what the big leagues were, how much money they made or nothing.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you have any more Comiskey stories?
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you think of anything else about Charlie, the old Roman?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'll tell you what kind of a man he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: When my youngest daughter was born, he sent her down one of the nicest go-karts you've ever laid eyes on with a gold plate on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: From Charles A. Comiskey to Irish Lucille Krause.
[SPEAKER_00]: Played about that long and about that wide.
[SPEAKER_00]: When was that?
[SPEAKER_00]: When was she born?
[SPEAKER_00]: Mom, when was Iris born?
[SPEAKER_02]: She was born in 25.
[SPEAKER_00]: 25, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he was, he was a real, he was a real old man, real old fella.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever see him lose his temper, or know about it at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: Never, I never, no, I never did.
[SPEAKER_00]: I saw Grabber lose his temper.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I never did see the chemistry with his temper.
[SPEAKER_01]: How about his relations with the ballplayers?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did he know them pretty well or come down to the clubhouse at all?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: He stayed up in the office.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why he was so happy to see me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I eventually say that...
[SPEAKER_00]: He may have been the only one up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was only about two or three that ever went up and talked to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he know the way?
[SPEAKER_00]: But he seemed really happy when I went in and talked to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: But they said, well...
[SPEAKER_00]: They said, I'm the only guy that ever grabbed or tear a contract off.
[SPEAKER_00]: I got a kick out of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, back in them days, the ballplayer didn't make the money.
[SPEAKER_00]: We were born 50 years too soon.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did you get your nickname?
[SPEAKER_00]: Now that's another funny thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're down in Florida, Spring Training, Johnny Evers gave me that nickname.
[SPEAKER_00]: I tried to pick a guy off of third base and threw one over Bill Cam's head.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the guy scored.
[SPEAKER_00]: He came in on an exhibition game and came in and sat down on the bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: I heard everyone hollering, Buck!
[SPEAKER_00]: But we had a colored trainer by the name of Buckner.
[SPEAKER_00]: They called him Buck.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I thought this guy was hollering at Buckner.
[SPEAKER_00]: He kept saying Buck and he kept getting louder.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't pay any attention to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: So when the game was over, up in the clubhouse, he come up to me and he said, look, he said, when I talk to you, I want you to answer me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I said, you wasn't talking to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I hollered Buck at least five minutes and you never paid any attention to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, my name's not Buck.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, my name is Clyde.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's not Buck.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, well, you know, he said,
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, I used to know a prize fighter in Pittsburgh by the name of Buck.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he said, I just got Buck in my mind.
[SPEAKER_00]: He called you Buck.
[SPEAKER_00]: From that day on, I was Buck.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, just pure chance or accident, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Had been fought and I could die.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was outfielder, fought, left fielder.
[SPEAKER_02]: Buck.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how I got my name.
[SPEAKER_01]: He just had it on his head, in his mind.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said he was thinking of this Buck Pricefighter.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, I thought you were talking to Buckner.
[SPEAKER_00]: We called him Buck, we called her Trainer.
[SPEAKER_01]: Everything was misunderstood, I think.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, so I didn't pay any attention to him.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were you called that for really quite a bit from then on?
[SPEAKER_00]: The rest of my life, that was it, Buck.
[SPEAKER_00]: What were you called before then?
[SPEAKER_00]: Clyde?
[SPEAKER_00]: Around here, Clyde, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: You mean the ballplayers?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But from that day on, all the ballplayers called me Buck.
[SPEAKER_00]: They followed me all the way through.
[SPEAKER_00]: The newspapers took it up?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sold me to Buffalo in 30.
[SPEAKER_00]: They started to call me Bucky instead of Buck.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the women.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'd say 90% of the fans in Buffalo were women.
[SPEAKER_00]: What year did you go to Buffalo?
[SPEAKER_00]: I went to Buffalo in the winter of 1930.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you stay all year with Buffalo?
[SPEAKER_00]: I stayed with Buffalo seven years.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that long?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Through 36?
[SPEAKER_00]: Up until the start of 37.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sold me to, traded me to Baltimore to become plan manager of Baltimore in 38, 37, 38.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that your first managerial job?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then how about 30?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you stay with them through 38?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then 39?
[SPEAKER_00]: 39 I sold myself, they released me in 38 and I sold myself to Little Rock.
[SPEAKER_00]: As a manager or?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, as a player.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I was with Little Rock a couple of months and talked them out of a release so I could go manage Montgomery, Alabama.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's also 39?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, 39.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's quite a long career though, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: You're over 40 now, aren't you?
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: The end of 39, I signed up with Indianapolis as a coach in Indianapolis.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's in 40.
[SPEAKER_00]: 1940, that's when I quit before.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was your last year?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: 20 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when I quit.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, now, did you ever catch a no-hitter?
[SPEAKER_01]: Did what?
[SPEAKER_01]: Ever catch a no-hitter?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I caught two no-hitters.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you tell me about them?
[SPEAKER_00]: I caught, they were in the big leagues.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I caught two no-hitters in Buffalo with
[SPEAKER_02]: And she said, I'm with her, I'm coming.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, you used to pitch for the Giants.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mom, what was that pitcher's name?
[SPEAKER_00]: His girl almost got killed.
[SPEAKER_02]: Harris?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Bill Harris.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Bill Harris, I caught.
[SPEAKER_00]: At Buffalo.
[SPEAKER_00]: I caught, I caught, almost caught a no-hitter for 10 lines in the big leagues with Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had Washington beat, if I remember right, the score was
[SPEAKER_00]: something like 11 or 12 to nothing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we had two men out in the ninth inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Walter Johnson was the manager of the club, and he sent in a pinch hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, wait a minute.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember whether Johnson was the manager of the club or not anyway.
[SPEAKER_00]: They sent in a pinch hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ted had two men out, and this guy come in here and bang.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had the line drive to the left field.
[SPEAKER_00]: Two men out in the night.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did Lyons feel?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he didn't feel good, but he didn't...
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, well, I'd rather he got a hit than not try to get one.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's what he said.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you go out and talk after that battle, or just let it go?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, just let it go.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, Lyons did pitch a no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was that his first year up, he pitched a no-hitter?
[SPEAKER_01]: In 23?
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember whether that was... No, that was the year Collins managed the club.
[SPEAKER_00]: 26.
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't catch that game, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I didn't catch... Oh, you mean when he... Pitched the one in the big one.
[SPEAKER_00]: When Ted Lyons pitched his no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I didn't catch him no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I've caught him a lot of games.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I caught most all of his games, but I didn't catch his no-hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was he a good pitcher to catch?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was one of the best pitchers, I thought, in the American League at that particular time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a change of pace that fooled his catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd have them hitters out there swinging way before
[SPEAKER_00]: He had a good fastball, good curve.
[SPEAKER_00]: What kind of signal did you have?
[SPEAKER_00]: Anything unusual?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, the only time we'd have anything unusual would be with a man on second base, and then we'd have a switch sign.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he couldn't pick up your signals, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I'd use my hand over my glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I put my hand over the glove, whatever I'd give would be the opposite.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the only sign we ever had.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did they pick up your signals very much, the third base coach?
[SPEAKER_00]: Not that I know of.
[SPEAKER_00]: I never heard anybody ever say that they could get my sign.
[SPEAKER_01]: Were there catchers who...
[SPEAKER_00]: They tried to.
[SPEAKER_00]: We've got a lot of other catcher signs because they hold their legs wide open, but I used to hold mine right together and hide my...
[SPEAKER_00]: The third base coach couldn't see my hand though.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did you have any pickoff plays?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I picked off quite a few at third base and first base.
[SPEAKER_00]: How did that work?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was that planned or just... Well, no, that's planned.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cam would give the play, playing third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: He may, well, he may touch his head or rub his chest.
[SPEAKER_00]: And who picks it up?
[SPEAKER_00]: You pick it up?
[SPEAKER_00]: I pick it up and answer.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got to answer.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then on the next pitch would be the play.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, we picked off, I pick off at least four or five every year.
[SPEAKER_01]: How would he know to make this play, when the bass runner's taking a big lead, or a certain type of bass runner?
[SPEAKER_00]: A certain, yeah, you gotta pick your bass runner, you gotta get an anxious sort of a bass runner, but he would play back, back a little deeper, and that, this guy'd take a little bigger lead.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he'd give me the play, and the minute he'd give it to me, we'd knock the hitter down.
[SPEAKER_00]: If he was a right-hand hitter, we'd knock him down.
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't know you did that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we knocked him down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we'd throw about that high over their heads.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's about six inches, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: And the minute he'd go down, all you got to do is catch and throw down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, on that very pitch?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you get him out of the way.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's done out of the way, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's quite a play, huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: You pick anybody off first base, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I picked a lot more off of first than I ever did off of... Would that be a play or just...
[SPEAKER_00]: It'd be the same kind of a play.
[SPEAKER_00]: It'd be an answer.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've, uh...
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I picked Ty Cobb off of second base one day.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: We had plays at every base.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did that happen?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he was taking that big lead.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was one of them... Cobb was a fellow that would dare.
[SPEAKER_00]: He would dare a young player.
[SPEAKER_00]: And his object was make you hustle your throw.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I'm not bragging, but they claim that I had one of the strongest arms in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: As a catcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I picked him off a third base and second base in the same game.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to have a write-up about that here in the paper.
[SPEAKER_00]: My grandkids got all my clippings.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he'd come in.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the first year up there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kid Gleason, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kid Gleason went out with a fun goal.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come in, he like tried to cut my head off with a plate.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd come in with his spike side when I cut him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I caught him off the third, you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: He came right in at you?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do?
[SPEAKER_01]: I left my mask on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you step aside and tag him?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was he out?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, he was out, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was tagged out at third base.
[SPEAKER_00]: What did he come in for?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just because I showed him up on a Sunday crowd call.
[SPEAKER_01]: You didn't have him even near that place, did you?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he didn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't know what happened to him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was that sort of a guy, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember one time when Ted Blankenship was pitching, and he was on a coach of mine.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd call Ted all kinds of names, try to get Ted mad, get him to fight, get him to
[SPEAKER_00]: He used to play, he used to, of course when I went up there he was playing a center field and manager club and he used to give a knockdown sign out there and everybody could see what he was doing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd signal the pitchers in center field what to throw.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, not what to throw, to knock the, knock the hitter down.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what to throw.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he had them filled well.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember the signal that he would give for that?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I didn't know what he did, but we knew that he was giving it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you ever...?
[SPEAKER_02]: He knocked Johnny Marshall down two or three times.
[SPEAKER_02]: I wonder why.
[SPEAKER_02]: He just figured the guy was going to hit, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you ever catch Cobb stealing, second, or...?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, I've caught him stealing a lot of times.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cobb, Ray Schalk tipped me off to Cobb.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cobb was a guy, when he took a big lead, he wouldn't run.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wouldn't run.
[SPEAKER_00]: When he took a short lead, he was gone.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, after I watched him just one time, I knew exactly what he was going to do.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's surprising nobody tipped Cobb off what he was doing.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's surprising nobody tipped Cobb off how he was giving himself away that way, isn't it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we had some pretty smart coaches.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had Chief Bender was one of our coaches, an old pitcher, Indian pitcher, and he was a pretty smart cookie.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's all he done, was just watch, whatever move they made.
[SPEAKER_00]: He told us a lot of things.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, after I got catching a few years and listened to shock, I could just about tell when a guy was going to run.
[SPEAKER_00]: You see, there's an anxious
[SPEAKER_00]: player, and then there's a guy a little more assertive, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you can almost tell.
[SPEAKER_01]: Have you watched Lou Brocksteel on television?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Have you been able to pick the time he's going to go?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, I haven't watched him that close.
[SPEAKER_00]: He runs on the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: He studies that pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: He knows every move that pitcher makes.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he knows exactly when a pitcher's going to throw it to play.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he's, he's really, he's a good baseball steward.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did you have a problem with any pitchers who, where the base runners wouldn't take advantage of the pitcher?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: We had, uh, we had a pitcher by the name of Leverett.
[SPEAKER_00]: Leverett couldn't hold him on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Faber was a tough guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: spitball pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was tough.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because every time a guy would steal, he'd throw a spitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that's about the only thing he had that he could...
[SPEAKER_00]: He didn't have much of a curve.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he threw a spitter almost 95% of the time.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was there some advantage in throwing that way?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, every time you throw a spitter, that spit is on the bottom.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when you grab that ball out of your glove, you got them two fingers right on that spit.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when you go to throw the second, you're throwing the spitter down there.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was rough.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to, I used to keep my glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: I used to keep, I used to keep dust in my glove, dirt in my glove.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when he threw that spitter with it, it wouldn't bother me too much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Was it hard to catch though, or hard to follow?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh yeah, he throwed a heavy ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Heavy ball?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, heavy and hard.
[SPEAKER_00]: What do you mean when you say heavy?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just dead weight, just... You know, a lot of fellas throw a real light ball, easy to handle.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then there's another fella throw a real heavy ball, just beats your hand up.
[SPEAKER_00]: My hand swell up that high every time I catch him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Couldn't already shut my hand.
[SPEAKER_01]: The ball didn't come fast, did it, but it just... Just heavy, just...
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it hard to, Cat, was it hard to keep in front of you or something, to get away from you?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no, it wasn't that... You see, today, the spitball pitch was knuckleball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Knuckleball, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Cat Lyons was a knuckleball pitcher, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he's hit me from the toes to the top of my head.
[SPEAKER_01]: But the spitball wasn't that hard to get in front of, was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: No, the spitball, you know, I knew exactly how it broke and everything.
[SPEAKER_00]: It came sharply down.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he could make it break in.
[SPEAKER_00]: He used to make a break in on Ruth's hands, made Ruth.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, I don't believe Ruth ever hit a home run off a favorite.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because he used to moan and groan every time favorite pitched, because favorite threw a spitter in on his hand.
[SPEAKER_01]: How often did he throw the spitter?
[SPEAKER_00]: About 95%.
[SPEAKER_01]: What else, what did he throw, what he wasn't?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just, he had a little curve, not much.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then a change up.
[SPEAKER_00]: But his best ball was a spitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why was that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Could you make contact with the spitter very much?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's hard to hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Hard to hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: You generally hit it on the ground.
[SPEAKER_01]: George Uley told me that in the 1920 World Series when Burleigh Grimes was pitching with the Dodgers against Cleveland, they noticed that the Brooklyn second baseman
[SPEAKER_01]: frequently, scooped up a handful of dirt.
[SPEAKER_01]: They knew that Brian was going to throw the spitter on that pitch, because in case it came grounding to him, he would, you know, he would slip on his hands, he'd get dripped on the dirt.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, every time they saw a second baseman scooping, they were expecting a spitter and laid off one.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, this Stanley Kolowicki of spitball pitcher cleaning was a rough guy to hit.
[SPEAKER_00]: That Yule, I never will forget it.
[SPEAKER_00]: The shot was through.
[SPEAKER_00]: Shock was a catch in this particular game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the bases are full.
[SPEAKER_00]: Along about the 6th or 7th inning.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'm down in the bullpen warming up for the pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they take Shock out for a pinch hitter because I hit left hand and they brought me in.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that yule, the first pitch he threw me was a changeup.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I swung, I swung on my hero.
[SPEAKER_00]: I bet that thing didn't go 10 feet.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right straight up in the air.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody on our bench fell off the bench.
[SPEAKER_00]: Whack.
[SPEAKER_01]: Mighty swing move.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I guess he was going to get a fastball in there and he had me figure just the same way and he said, well, I'll just slow it up on this one.
[SPEAKER_00]: Pretty smart pitcher.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he was one of the smartest pitchers Cleveland had.
[SPEAKER_01]: yeah he won a lot more games in his armor than he did he had a bad arm by the end of the year yeah he won over 200 games I guess Ruth never hit a home run off of you that's right I don't know I don't think he ever did off of Faber he hit home runs over Thomas I saw him hit a home run yeah if I'm one with a
[SPEAKER_00]: in Comiskey Park, from over the top in right field.
[SPEAKER_00]: I saw him hit line drives in the left field stands.
[SPEAKER_00]: I remember, I remember one game that little Mike Savendro's left-hand pitcher, pitching for us.
[SPEAKER_00]: This was 1923, and I was catching the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Mike wanted to walk him.
[SPEAKER_02]: We had him beat two to one.
[SPEAKER_00]: And there was a man on second base.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mike wanted to walk through.
[SPEAKER_00]: First base was open.
[SPEAKER_00]: But Kid Gleason wouldn't let him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Kid Gleason, after the game was over, he said, look, he said, the people come out to see that big, he called him a big monkey.
[SPEAKER_00]: They come out to see him swing.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't come out to see him walk.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the first pitch Mike threw him was a curveball, sidearm curve.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he was fooled on it.
[SPEAKER_00]: He swung and he let loose of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: With his left hand, as you come around, with one hand, he had a line driver, left field stance.
[SPEAKER_00]: So Van Gogh just dropped his head.
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, that really hurt him.
[SPEAKER_00]: One-handed.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the reason was that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: He wanted to please the fans.
[SPEAKER_00]: He said, the fans didn't come out here.
[SPEAKER_00]: Of course, Mike wanted to win the game.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we could have walked him.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, first base open.
[SPEAKER_00]: Who was up next to him?
[SPEAKER_00]: It wasn't Gary, he wasn't up there then.
[SPEAKER_00]: Gary wasn't up there then.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: It was a big center fielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: Witt.
[SPEAKER_02]: Why are you Witt?
[SPEAKER_00]: Huh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Witt.
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was his name.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who are you talking about now, honey?
[SPEAKER_00]: Can't think of his name now, but he was a center fielder.
[SPEAKER_02]: Who, Dad?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yankees.
[SPEAKER_00]: Coombs.
[SPEAKER_00]: Earl Coombs.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's down in Richmond, Indiana, or Kentucky.
[SPEAKER_01]: Earl is?
[SPEAKER_01]: I haven't interviewed him.
[SPEAKER_01]: He's not well.
[SPEAKER_01]: Don't forget that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: You mentioned Johnny Walsall.
[SPEAKER_01]: Didn't he commit, try to commit suicide?
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: Anything about that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, sure.
[SPEAKER_00]: We was,
[SPEAKER_00]: spring training in Shreveport, Louisiana.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'm trying to think who the manager was.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think, again, I think Eddie Collins was the manager.
[SPEAKER_00]: Must have been 26.
[SPEAKER_00]: Anyway, we're in Shreveport, Louisiana, and it rained.
[SPEAKER_00]: Our game was off.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, ballplayers generally
[SPEAKER_00]: Got a little Porter game to go on.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we're all, we're all in this room playing poker.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Barrett ruined with Johnny.
[SPEAKER_02]: Bill who?
[SPEAKER_00]: Bill Barrett.
[SPEAKER_00]: Barrett.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a what?
[SPEAKER_00]: He was an outfielder, an infielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: But in the media, if I understand it right, Barrett, monstrous girl, fell in love with Bill Barrett.
[SPEAKER_00]: or vice versa, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Anyway, Barrett married this girl.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know that, so it must have been true.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we're all over in this room playing cards, and Barrett goes out of the room to try to get in the room, and he can't get in.
[SPEAKER_00]: Johnny's in there, and he locked the door on the inside.
[SPEAKER_00]: So he had to call for a bellboy to bring a passkey up to open the door.
[SPEAKER_00]: When they opened the door, they saw blood coming out of the bathroom floor, where he was in the bathroom.
[SPEAKER_00]: He cut his wrist.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, he cut all them arteries by now.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had left arm.
[SPEAKER_00]: Both hands.
[SPEAKER_00]: Instead of even cutting it, he'd throw it this way, cut it down, down that-a-way.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I guess he'd have bled to death in another... What'd they do when they found him?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, they called the ambulance and rushed him to the hospital right away.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, of course, the following year he wasn't able to play at all.
[SPEAKER_00]: He kept a little hard ball in his hand like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he finally come back, come back the following year and played.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then he broke his leg in Detroit.
[SPEAKER_00]: Turned his ankle just completely around in Detroit the following year.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he, he finally became coach of the
[SPEAKER_00]: Socks.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he have any good years after that?
[SPEAKER_00]: No.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a pretty good hitter.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was the best outfielder.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was one of the best center fielders in the game at that time.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was like this guy with Cincinnati.
[SPEAKER_00]: He'd go back and get them.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, he was a real good ball player.
[SPEAKER_01]: Did anybody ever talk much about this afterwards?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: How did the players handle him when he recovered?
[SPEAKER_00]: They treated him just like they always did.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was just a lovesick guy, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, sure was.
[SPEAKER_00]: In fact, this youngest son of mine, Ron, was here.
[SPEAKER_00]: John signed him to the White South contract when I took him up to Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's dead now, Johnny is.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a little bit off, I think, anyway, but I brought him down here one fall to hunt with me.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're out here on a farm with one of the mail carriers.
[SPEAKER_00]: Out on a farm, and there's four of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we get through hunting, and he had a brand new pump gun.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he hadn't ever hunted, so we kept him on the far side of us.
[SPEAKER_00]: But when we come in and started unloading, we're all standing around in a circle.
[SPEAKER_00]: And we went out there with this mailman's old Ford, old T-model Ford.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's pumping the shells out of this thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he didn't pump the last one out.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he pulled the trigger.
[SPEAKER_00]: That bullet went right between me and this mailman.
[SPEAKER_00]: He shot a whole lot of old T-models for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: About that big, blowing all the wires off of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: We couldn't run.
[SPEAKER_00]: I had to call up and have him bring my car out to get us.
[SPEAKER_00]: When we got home that night, my wife was cooking supper.
[SPEAKER_00]: We're sitting at the supper table eating.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he looked at me and he said, Buck, he said, he said, I don't mind giving that guy $80 to fix that car.
[SPEAKER_00]: But he said, that old Ford wasn't worth $80.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the only client the mailman had to carry the mail in.
[SPEAKER_00]: I said, well, yeah, John was worth more than $80.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was something.
[SPEAKER_01]: You think he was a little eccentric?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, he was.
[SPEAKER_00]: Did he ever marry?
[SPEAKER_00]: Never did marry.
[SPEAKER_00]: As far as I know, he never did.
[SPEAKER_00]: Where did he live?
[SPEAKER_00]: in Whiting, Indiana.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right out of Chicago.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you a funny thing about him.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a pretty good third baseman too.
[SPEAKER_00]: And something happened in Washington to Bill Camp.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they bring John in on third.
[SPEAKER_00]: And John was the guy, when he was out in the outfield, the minute the ball was hit, he'd holler, I got it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Bibb Falkhurst, you know Bibb, he'd just say, come on John, get it!
[SPEAKER_00]: A foul ball goes up behind me, behind the plate, and I'm back there just getting ready to catch it.
[SPEAKER_00]: When John went, pew, by me and grabbed it.
[SPEAKER_00]: From third base, come up there behind home plate and grabbed that ball.
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it a regular league game?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, in Washington.
[SPEAKER_00]: I like to die, and I said, come on, John.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that's the kind of guy I was.
[SPEAKER_00]: The minute the ball's hit, he's got it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I won't forget, Harry Hooper on one side and then Bibb Fogg on the other.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they'd say, come on, John.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tell me about Bibb Fogg.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bibb Fogg, he was quite a guy.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a real left-hander.
[SPEAKER_00]: He was a good ballplayer.
[SPEAKER_01]: When you say a left-hander, what are you referring to there?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we always call most left-handers wild, you know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Viv lived in Austin, Texas, I believe is where he lived.
[SPEAKER_00]: But we used to have a lot of fun with old Viv.
[SPEAKER_01]: How do you mean?
[SPEAKER_01]: What did you do?
[SPEAKER_01]: Just play jokes?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just joke with each other.
[SPEAKER_01]: Do you remember any of them that might be of interest to future historians?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, I don't remember.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't remember offhand.
[SPEAKER_01]: He was quite a bench jockey, eh?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: A little set of stuff he did there.
[SPEAKER_01]: He'd sit on that bench and holler at everybody.
[SPEAKER_00]: I was trying to think of the little fella that managed the St. Louis Browns.
[SPEAKER_00]: Puggins?
[SPEAKER_00]: What was it?
[SPEAKER_00]: That'd be earlier.
[SPEAKER_00]: Little bit of a fella.
[SPEAKER_00]: Anyway, Bibb used to, boy, he used to ride that guy.
[SPEAKER_02]: I can't think of the name.
[SPEAKER_02]: Austin?